Joash Agesa

Software Engineer

joashagesa@yahoo.com

0

in



0

About

I, Joash Agesa, am a Software Engineer. My passion for software lies in dreaming up ideas and making them come true. My projects consistently reflect attention to detail in: user experience, architecture, and code quality.

I am an open-source enthusiast. I love its aspect of collaboration and knowledge sharing. I am happy to see how what I do could eventually give back to the community and industry.

Working with me is enriching. I bring technical expertise, creativity, and dedication to every project. On top of that, I am always open to learn and adapt.

Projects

CodeGround ♥ 7

An Educational Online Code Editor powered by Al Documentation



100 days Challenge ♥ 7

100 days of design challenge



Beeetle 7

An embeddable Chat Wigdet with ai powered conversation

More Projects...

Work Experience

Wezeshanet Technologies Software Engineer

Jan 2024 - Present | Remote

In Automation and Solutions Department

Building systems and creating products that deliver core services.

Virtualweb Technologies Frontend Developer

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023 | Remote

In Development and Engineering Department

- Developed mobile applications for business ventures
- Designed and Developed the Cloud Access Portal for end users

SiafuSocial Ltd. Technical Lead

May 2023 - Nov 2023 | Nairobi, Kenya

In Product R & D and Engineering Architecture Department

- Collaboratively remediated 120+ software anomalies, contributing to user-centric features via reusable code.
- Verified and optimized feasibility of 100+ UI/UX designs for 2+ applications.
- Implementing security measures such as encryption, authentication, and authorization.
- Optimizing backend code and database queries to improve application performance and response times.

Herufi Technologies Ltd. Frontend Developer Intern

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022 | Nairobi, Kenya

In Product Development Team

- Built an Ecommerce website for a Distribution Company in Nairobi called Marsyetu
- Collaborated with a team of other developers, exercising proper collaborative culture

Stacks

Frontend TypeScript, JavaScript, Vue, Nuxt, React, Next.js, Vite

Backend Node, GraphQL, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Serverless, Nginx, Docker, Dokku

Mobile Android, Kotlin, React Native, PWA

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Azure

Languages Python, Java, C/C++, C#, Go

Education

Computer Software Engineering, Bachelor of Science - BS, Kirinyaga University

Sep 2019 - Sep 2023

Languages

Swahili (Native speaker), English (Fluent), Japanese (Beginner)

Online Version

Last updated at March 2nd 2024, 5:21:30 pm